SUYOG JADHAV

MACHINE LEARNING DEVELOPER



+91 7719058077









suyog.17je002775@ece.ism.ac.in

PROFILE

Skilled in the fields of machine learning, deep learning, data science, competitive programming and competitive data science. Experienced in TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn, XGBoost. Can code in Python(2/3), C++, C and MATLAB/GNU Octave.

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning

Stanford University on Coursera

Advanced Machine Learning Specialization

HSE - National Research University on Coursera

- Introduction to Deep Learning (with Honors)
- How to Win a Data Science Competition: Learn from Top Kagglers (with Honors)

Deep Learning Specialization

deeplearning.ai on Coursera

- Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects

SKILLS

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- TensorFlow
- Keras
- Competitive Programming
- Competitive Data Science
- Regex

EXPERIENCE

Cyber Labs, AI Team Member

APR 2018 - PRESENT

Currently, a member of the AI team of Cyber Labs, the cyber society of IIT (ISM), Dhanbad. The team is focused on working on various projects related to AI.

ML Endeavours. Editor

APR 2018 - PRESENT

Blogs about created projects and about machine learning, in general.

Coursera. Course Mentor

JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Currently, mentoring the course "Introduction" to Deep Learning" by HSE - National Research University on Coursera.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Technology (Indian School of Mines). Dhanbad

2017 - 2021

Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering

PES Modern College of Arts, Science and Commerce, Shivajinagar, Pune

2015 - 2017

11th &12th Std. (Science)

LANGUAGES

Python (2/3) | C++ | C | Matlab | GNU Octave | CSS

PROJECTS



FaceSearch

JUL 2018

Motivation: To create a simple tool that lets us search online for unknown persons in an image. Can be used to know the name of a person from his/her face.

Used OpenCV to create a simple command line tool that takes as input path of an image (can be internet URL as well), detects faces in them and prompts the user which faces he wants to search for. After the user clicks on the face of his choice, the face is then uploaded to the Google and uses opens a new window in the browser with Google reverse image search results for the image.



Emotion Recognition

MAR 2018 - PRESENT

Motivation: Recognize facial expressions using a webcam, live in the browser.

The frontend is built using Nodejs. For the backend, used keras with Tensorflow backend. The web app first takes the live stream from the webcam and saves images at a fixed rate. The frontend then sends the images to a python script that detects and crops out faces from the images and returns the predicted predictions. The frontend is built by Ujjawal Jaiswal, a fellow member of the Web Development team at Cyber Labs.



Devanagari Numbers Recognition

MAR 2018 - PRESENT

Motivation: A python script that tries to recognize Devanagari numbers in the provided image.

Built using Keras with TensorFlow backend. 91.49% accuracy on the validation set as of now.